

About me

An experienced developer in React and Javascript. I enjoy creating products that have a positive impact on their users.

Skills

Effective communication.
Spelling and writing.
Figma and Framer.
Javascript, Typescript, ES6.
React, Nextjs, Redux.
Node, Svelte, Webpack.
CSS, Tailwind.
Wordpress, WooCommerce and other CMS.
Adobe Suit (Launch, AEM, Campaign)

Languages

Spanish.
English (Advanced).
French (intermediate).
Russian (beginner).

My projects

Sticky covers 12 Sholomitos 12

Awards/Achievements

Best insurance app in 2021 [2]

work@pablovazquez.simplelogin.com

(462) 264 1459 github.com/elpablazo

Pablo Vázquez

Fullstack Developer

Top Work experience

FORD MÉXICO [2

I generate, analyze, and optimize analytics on the Ford and Lincoln Mexico website. (As VML employee)

November 2024 - Actual

WOOW ¡TODO BIEN! ☐

I programmed the company's most popular product: Pet insurance. (As PROTEC employee)

November 2020 - June 2021

PIF LIVERPOOL & SUBURBIA

I designed and coded the "Protección Integral y Familiar" platform for Liverpool and Suburbia. (As PROTEC employee) November 2020 - June 2021

CAPITAL EXPERIENCIAS [2]

I coded a real time experiences and prizes platform. *(As freelancer)* 2022

More below

Education

Computer engineering Instituto Politécnico Nacional 2017 - 2022



World Friends Languages (2023)

I am designing, coding and engineering a language learning platform that can help students all over the world get connected with professional teachers. Built in Next.js and Tailwind on the front, and using Mongo DB and Payload on the back, along with various react-specific libraries such as zustand, Formik and Framer.

Caradebola (2022)

I reengineered the chekout and display process of a popular fashion brand that helps connect illustrators with clients interested on buying merchandise. The site migrated from a custom backend to Wordpdress and Woocommerce, along with other plugins such as stores, carts and orders. Developed in React using Nextjs.

Capital Experiencias (2022)

I coded the website of a platform that delivers real time experiencies related to events, prizes and raffles that connects technologies like websockets, YouTube APIs, complex animations in Rive, React Framer and payment methods like Mercado Pago into a custom backend. Developed in React using Nextjs.

Azteca Tools (2022)

I reengineered the checkout process of a popular hardware store to be able to work with Wordpress and Woocommerce, allowing the use WP plugins such as carts, custom orders and payment integrations. Developed in React using Nextjs and TailwindCSS.

SHOLOMITOS (2022 -)

I own, designed and coded a dropshipping marketplace for dog food that can deliver products with free shipping cost, using Stripe as payment solution. Developed in React using Nextjs, TailwindCSS.

STICKY COVERS (2021 -)

I own, desgined, develop, maintain and improve my personal ecommerce site <u>stickycovers.com</u> using Next.js, a modified version of TailwindCSS and Strapi as a headless CMS. Hosted in Vercel (front) and Heroku (back) with Cloudinary and PostGresQL database. I am also in charge of the advertisement, social networks, SEO and product image and placement.

WOOOW, ¡TODO BIEN! (2020 - 2021)

Developed the star product of a micro-insurance service startup: Pet insurance. I helped fixing bugs, developing new features and improving the performance of the site for other products like medical care, car insurance, gadgets insurance, etc. By using react, a modified version of Bootstrap and Codelgniter.

PLATAFORMA PIF (2020 - 2021)

I desgined, developed, tested and maintained the internal website and platform for the "Protección integral familiar" department of all Liverpool and Suburbia stores in México.

CLUB DE ASISTENCIA (2020 - 2021)

I desgined the internal platform that helps to manage the complains, incidents and troubleshoot of Club de asistencia, using React and TailwindCSS.

NOOK Models Management (2020)

Developed the site of a popular model's agency using next.js and TailwindCSS, hosted in Digital Ocean using Nginx and Strapi as a headless CMS.

Lionbridge: Assesor (2018 - 2020)

I helped Google improve its locale's results in México, by adding context to the user's searchs based on the revelance, liability, professionality and SEO of the websites that the page showed up.



Perfil

Desarrollador con experiencia en React y Javascript. Disfruto de crear servicios que tienen un impacto positivo en la vida de sus usuarios.

Habilidades

Comunicación efectiva.
Redacción y ortografía.
Figma y Framer.
Javascript, Typescript, ES6.
React, Nextjs, Redux.
Node, Svelte, Webpack.
CSS, Tailwind.
Wordpress, Woocommerce y otros CMS.
Adobe Suit (Launch, AEM, Campaign)

Idiomas

Español. Inglés. Francés (intermedio). Ruso (básico).

Proyectos Personales

Sticky covers **Sholomitos Sholomitos**

Contacto

<u>work@pablovazquez.simplelogin.com</u> (462) 264 1459

Pablo Vázquez

Desarrollador fullstack

Experiencia laboral

FORD.MX [2]

Genero, analizo y optimizo analíticas en el sitio de Ford y Lincoln México. *(En VML)* Noviembre 2024 - Actual

PIF LIVERPOOL Y SUBURBIA □

Diseñé y desarrollé la plataforma de Protección Integral Familiar para Liverpool y Suburbia. *(En PROTEC)* Noviembre 2020 - Junio 2021

WOOW ¡TODO BIEN! ☐

Desarrollé el producto estrella: Seguros para mascota. *(En PROTEC)* Noviembre 2020 - Junio 2021

CAPITAL EXPERIENCIAS ☑

Desarrollé una plataforma de rifas, sorteos y experiencias en tiempo real. (As freelancer) 2022

Historial académico

Ingeniería en Computación Instituto Politécnico Nacional 2017 - 2022

Reconocimientos

Mejor aplicación en la categoría de seguros 🖸